### linkedin.com/in/avinash-sivaraman

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Computer Science graduate with a focus on Software, Web and Machine learning. Interested in a career as a Software Engineer. I've prior industry experience at Goldman Sachs, as New Analyst Programmer Associate (NAPA) in the Engineering division on

• Software Development

• Web development (React)

Testing and Automation

• Platform engineering

### **EDUCATION**

# **Master of Science – Computer Science**

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ GPA 3.66 / 4.0

May 2020

Bachelor of Technology – Information Science and Technology

College of Engineering, Guindy, Chennai, IND GPA 8.9/10

May 2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

### **Graduate Service Assistant**

Sep 2018 – Current

## Formative Assessment with Computational Technologies (FACT) Project Lab, AZ

- Working as **React Developer** in harnessing the analytic power of computer-supported collaborative learning and intelligent tutoring systems.
- Redesigned the build system to latest version to improve the performance of the application.
- Created an end-to-end demo workflow in the existing application.

## **Technology Analyst**

Jun 2016 - Jul 2018

### Goldman Sachs, Bangalore, IND

- Worked on Distributed Trade Processing (DARTS) Team under Goldman Sachs Asset Management (GSAM).
- Developed a Web User Interface using **React and Redux** to monitor, search, amend and cancel the trades booked by traders.
- Achieved an increase in performance of 75% by identifying the minimal representation of a UI state and reducing the bundle size of the application.

# Summer Intern

May 2015 – July 2015

### Goldman Sachs, Bangalore, IND

- Implemented the Automated Testing using JBehave for Central Trading Desk Team to improve the code quality and reach the high Test Maturity Model (TMM) level.
- Test coverage includes **70%** of the application.

### ACADEMIC PROJECTS

## Information Retrieval and Analysis – Dataset: DIV150CRED

Fall 2018

- Used textual and visual descriptors to parse the given user, location and visual data and implemented functionality that aims to reduce the dimensionality of data using factorization techniques like SVD, PCA, LDA, and Tensor Decomposition.
- Improved data retrieval by using algorithms such as **clustering**, **personalized page rank**, **classification**, **and locality sensitive hashing**. NumPy and Scikit python libraries are used to solve the problem.

### **Choice of Plausible Alternatives – COPA Challenge**

**Fall 2018** 

- Designed and Developed an NLP system to solve COPA challenge by using web corpus and causal networks.
- Constructed a best possible query of keywords for the sentences and alternatives to find the perfect match in the web. **Stanford Core NLP** python kit is used to parse the sentence into it part of speech.
- Used **K-Parser** to compare the actual sentence and web corpus data.

## American Sign Language (ASL) – Android Project

**Fall 2018** 

- Created a Machine Learning (ML) powered **Android** application to enable easy learning of ASL signs.
- Built a Model using **Decision Tree classification** to detect the word from the recorded video.

# **Dynamic Fairness Scheduling – Openstack**

Fall & Spring 2016

- Achieved a high throughput in scheduling each node using "Best Fit Scheduler" and "Live migration support".
- Used Arima Time series model in predicting the node usage to improve the scheduling.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS & RELEVANT COURSES

**Programming**: JavaScript, Python, Shell, C, C++, Java

Framework: React, Redux, NodeJS, RxJS, NumPy, SciKit, React Native, Android, MySQL, Mongo Web Technology, Multimedia and Web Databases, Natural Language Processing, Mobile Computing, Data Analysis, Distributed System, Cloud Computing, Unix internals.